Richard Fox

Address: Kensal Rise, London, W10

Nationality: British

Email: rjfox321@gmail.com LinkedIn: <u>uk.linkedin.com/in/rjfox</u> DOB. 17/10/1985

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Creative minded games programmer with a wide skills base and 10+ years commercial programming experience including three years in the games industry. I am committed to furthering my career in games development and working with passionate people on stimulating projects.

SKILLS

- Languages C++, C#, Java, Objective-C
- Engines Unreal Engine 4, Unity3D
- 3D OpenGL/ES, GLSL Direct X9, HLSL and related 3D maths.
- Web Javascript, HTML5, Google Web Toolkit
- Game Libs Cocos2D/-X, Box2D, PhysX, Bullet Physics, AssImp
- IDE- Visual Studio 2005-2017, MonoDevelop, Eclipse, Xcode, VS6.
- Database MS SQL Server 2005, 2008, TSQL, Database Design, Admin, ADO/.net
- General Libs WinAPI and STL
- Source Control Perforce, GIT, SVN, Mercurial, VSS.
- Computing Theory Agile, OOP
- Content Creation 3d Studio Max, Photoshop CS, Flash, GIMP

EMPLOYMENT

• Imaginati Studios (May 2016 – June 2018)

Senior Programmer

Planet of the Apes: Last Frontier (PS4, XboxOne, PC/Steam)

Full cycle narrative game from virtual slice to release, built using UE4. Prototyping, Level streaming, local multiplayer, UMG, dynamic audio sequencer plugin, engine extension, alterations and updates. Video generation tools, Console submission / TRC's and patches. Playstation PlayLink and Wifi hotspot integration, Microsoft Mixer integration, Steam integration.

Management of junior coders, mentoring, scheduling.

Holistic City Ltd (Sister company of Oxford Numerics) (March 2013 – May 2016)
 Software Developer

Tasks – Programming features in CityCAD 3D urban planning software, C#, Managed DirectX, UI, xml data structures, ffmpeg video encoding, SSAO implementation, Conversion to SharpDX, custom graphing component creation using GDI+, Unity WebGL browser interaction.

Oxford Numerics (Sister company of Holistic City) (March 2013 – May 2016)

Software Developer

Tasks – Oilfield engineering software. System architecture, MVP, C# Winforms, XML, Managed DirectX oil well visualisation, C++/CLI interface layer to serve native simulators, threading, advanced charting, major commonality refactoring and componentising.

• Ramtac Computer Systems Ltd (October 2012 – March 2013)

Software Developer

Tasks – Plugin development for stock management / accounting software. C#, MSSQL, client facing requirement & specification, UI design patterns (MVC, MVP).

Worldweaver Ltd (October 2011 – September 2012)

Software Developer

<u>MazeWalker</u> (iOS) – Programmer using Objective-C, XCode and cocos2d. Tools programming in the form of a level editor using C# and XML.

<u>BattlePens</u> prototype – Developed prototype using Google Web Toolkit(GWT) / HTML5 canvas and Google App Engine(GAE) cloud services.

DinoTrouble prototype (unreleased) – Cross-platform mobile games development using cocos2d-x, C++ and VS2010. A* path finding, Box2D physics.

Military simulation and training software (web/dx studio plugin) - development in a larger team using existing in-house games engine including some SQL database design and development and supporting C# codebase. 3D radio signal graphing.

Esperus Systems Ltd (April 2010 – October 2011)

Developer

Tasks – Lead developer maintaining the 'Genesis' stock management system, Optimisation of slow functions/queries, liaising with testing and support teams on bugs and client feedback, Req/Spec of additional Genesis development requests, C# Tools/Utilities, full development lifecycle of new internal bug, development & call logging system (C#), Data Warehousing, Com interop, Development of SQL data structures updater, Assist development of .Net web services and applications, Crystal reports design and development, SVN server setup and maintenance.

• Esperus Systems Ltd (June 2008 – April 2010)

Junior Developer / Support Engineer

Tasks – Assist maintaining existing 'Genesis' windows based retail/wholesale stock management system code base. Vb6/vb.net, Crystal Report 9+ reports, UI design, MS SQL 2005+ database design, deployment and administration, client requirement gathering/analysis, client training seminars.

EDUCATION

Goldsmiths University (Sept 2014 – Sept 2016)

MSc (Distinction) Computer Games & Entertainment

A computer science masters degree focusing on C++, games programming, mathematics, 3D graphics and Al. Projects include Procedural Terrain Generation, Perlin noise, LSystems, Bullet physics game, Procedurally generated creatures (metaballs), Genetic Algorithm based Tower Defense Unity game, C++ Multiplayer networking, OpenGL component based games engine. See portfolio site for video based demos

University of Lincoln (Sept 2004 – July 2007)

BSc (Hons) Software Development (Games Computing)

A computer science degree specialising into games / graphics technology towards the latter part of the course. Focus on C++ with 3D graphics (OpenGL), mobile games programming in Java and HL2 Source games engine.

- SEEVIC College, Benfleet, Essex (Sept 2002 July 2004)
 - A 'Level Business Studies Grade A
 - A' Level Computing Grade B
 - A' Level Psychology Grade C
- King Edmund School, Rochford, Essex (Sept 1997 July 2002)
 11 GCSE's including Math, English, Science, IT, Business.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

- <u>Sealife Scramble</u> Unity based endless runner game targeting iOS/Andriod and web. Working with small
 international team as programming lead in my spare time. 2D using built-in (box2d) physics and NGUI.
- Code Name Spy (UKIE gamejam winner)
- Games Engine Development of a basic C++/Direct-X 9 games engine for personal use and learning.
 Includes basic implementations of terrain rendering/generation, skinned mesh animation, particle systems, skymaps, shadow volumes and a toon shader.
- Various GameJam projects
- Arx (WIP) Team based multiplayer game built on UE4.